Georg J.P. Link

https://georg.link/
orcid.org/0000-0001-6769-7867

SUMMARY

My research advances our knowledge in corporate engagement with open source projects. As corporate involvement increases, open source foundations provide guidance and support for open source projects. We only begin to understand the evolution of this triangular relationship. My current research focus is to inform this relationship through research into open source project health and new market mechanisms. My work has been accepted to the Communications of the Association for Information Systems, the Journal for Universal Computer Science, CSCW, ACM GROUP, Americas Conference on Information Systems, OpenSym, HICSS, CHAOSSCon, and MWAIS. My research has been supported by the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, Mozilla, and the Linux Foundation.

I am engaged at both professional and university levels. I volunteered at various academic conferences, was a conference co-organizer for the 2017 Big XII+ MIS Symposium and 2018 CHAOSScon, am currently the Communications Chair for AIS SIGOPEN, and am an active member of the University of Nebraska at Omaha's BRIDGE Lab — a lab dedicated to the advancement of IT design, architecture, and education. Finally, I am an active member in the Linux Foundation CHAOSS project and the Mozilla Bugmark project.

EDUCATION

University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA

■ Ph.D. in Information Technology planned May, 2019

- Dissertation: Cooperative Signaling Behavior: Signals for Open Source Project Health
- Advisor: Prof. Matt Germonprez
- Focus: Open Source Community Health

■ MBA – Master of Business Administration 2013

- Concentration: Collaboration Science
- Cumulative GPA: 3.9 / 4.0

Technical University Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany

- M.S. in Business Informatics 2014
 - Thesis: Evaluating Anchored Discussion as a New Tool for Creativity in Online Collaboration
 - \bullet Cumulative GPA: 1.3 (German grade translates to 3.7 / 4.0)

WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany

- B.A. in Business Administration 2011
 - Concentration: Banking
 - Cumulative GPA: 1.8 (German grade translates to 3.2 / 4.0)

GRANT FUNDING Total: \$11,415.00

■ \$1,851.00 - Linux Foundation	2018
Travel support to Open Source Summit Europe, Edinburgh, UK	

2018

- \$805.00 Linux Foundation
- Travel support to Open Source Summit North America, Vancouver, Canada
- \$2,441.00 Mozilla
 Travel support to ACM Collective Intelligence, Zurich, Switzerland
- \$1,318.00 Linux Foundation 2017
- Travel support to Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, CA, USA
- \$5,000.00 University of Nebraska at Omaha 2017
 - Program: Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA)

 Research and Creative Activity (GRACA)

 Research and Creative Activity (GRACA)
 - Proposal title: The Changing Nature of Volunteerism in Open Source Communities

SCHOLARSHIPS

Hanns-Seidel-Stiftung	2012 - 2014
 German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD) 	2012 - 2013
 College of Information Science and Technology, University of Nebraska at Omaha 	2015 - 2016

HONORS & AWARDS

- Doctoral Student Service Award, Association for Information Systems
 Best Paper Award, AIS SIG GlobDev
 2017
 - Link, G. J.P., & Qureshi, S. (2017). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development.
 In Proceedings of the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems. Boston.

2008

PUBLICATIONS UNDER REVIEW (2)

- Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (initial submission on 10/15/2018). A Market for Trading Software Issues. *Journal of Cybersecurity*
- Link, G. J.P., J. Kowal, S. Qureshi (third revision due 2/28/2019). Open Source in Development: Enabling Business and Services. *Information Systems Management*.

JOURNALS PEER-REVIEWED (2)

- 2018 Link, G. J.P., M. Rao, D. Mari, A. Leak, R. Bodo Marktplatz zur Kollaboration und Finanzierung von Open Source Software. *HMD Praxis der Wirtschaftsinformatik*. https://doi.org/10.1365/s40702-018-00474-6
- 2016 Link, G. J.P., D. Siemon, G. de Vreede, S. Robra-Bissantz (2016). Anchored Discussion: Development of a Tool for Creativity in Online Collaboration, *Journal for Universal Computer Science*, 22(10), 1339–1359. https://doi.org/10.3217/jucs-022-10-1339

JOURNALS EDITORIALLY-REVIEWED (2)

- 2018 Link, G. J.P., K. Lumbard, N. Damen, H. Rosser, M. Germonprez, S. Goggins, A. Wiggins, V. Ahuja, J. brier, J. Cohoon, A. Halfaker, J. Howison, D. Marti, G. Newman, C. Østerlund, R. Paik, B. Rother, A. Schecter (accepted 9/3/2018). Open Community Health: Workshop Report. *Journal of Peer Production*, Issue 13.
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, K. Lumbard, K. Conboy, M. Feldman, J. Feller, J. George, M. Germonprez, S. Goggins, D. Jeske, G. Kiely, K. Schuster, M. Willis (2017). Contemporary issues of open data in Information Systems research: Considerations and recommendations. *Communications of the Association for Information Systems*, *41*(Article 25), 587–610. http://aisel.aisnet.org/cais/vol41/iss1/25/

CONFERENCES (14)

- 2018 Germonprez, M., <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Lumbard, K., & Goggins, S. (2018). Eight Observations and 24 Research Questions About Open Source Projects: Illuminating New Realities. Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction, 2(CSCW), 57:1–57:22. https://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/isqafacpub/64/
- 2018 <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Germonprez, M. (2018). Assessing open source project health. Proceedings of the Twenty-fourth Americas Conference on Information Systems 2018. New Orleans, LA. http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2018/Openness/Presentations/5
- 2018 Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (2018). A trading market for prices in peer production. Proceedings of ACM Collective Intelligence. Zurich, Switzerland.
- 2018 Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (2018). A Trading Market to Incentivize Secure Software. Proceedings of the 17th Annual Workshop on the Economics of Information Security (WEIS), Innsbruck, Austria. https://weis2018.econinfosec.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2016/09/WEIS_2018_paper_27.pdf
- 2018 Gandhi, R., Germonprez, M., & Link, G. J.P.*(2018). Open data standards for open source software risk management routines: An examination of SPDX. Proceedings of the ACM GROUP'18, Sanibel Island. https://doi.org/10.1145/3148330.3148333
- 2018 <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Qureshi, S. (2018). The role of open source communities in development: Policy implications for governments. Presented at the HICSS 2018, Hawaii. http://hdl.handle.net/10125/50190
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u> (2017). The value of engaging with open source communities. In *OpenSym '17 Companion*. Galway, Ireland: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3126673.3126679
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Jeske, D. (2017). Understanding organization and open source community relations through the Attraction-Selection-Attrition Model. In *OpenSym '17 Companion*. Galway, Ireland: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3125433.3125472

^{*}Authors in alphabetical order

- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Qureshi, S. (2017). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. In *Proceedings of the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems*. Boston. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2017/ICTs/Presentations/18/
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> Gill, J., & Khazanchi, D. (2017). Measuring adoption of open source software and practices in organizations: A pilot study. In *Proceedings of the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference*. Springfield, IL. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/mwais2017/43/
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Lumbard, K., Germonprez, M., & Goggins, S. (2017). Advancing open online community science practice: The open community data exchange. In *Proceedings of the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference*. Springfield, IL. http://aisel.aisnet.org/mwais2017/44
- 2016 Link, G. J.P., Germonprez, M., Goggins, S., Hemsley, J., Rand, B., & Squire, M. (2016). The Open Community Data Exchange: Advancing data sharing and discovery in open online community science. In *OpenSym '16 Companion*. Berlin, Germany: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/2962132. 2962142
- 2016 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, & Germonprez, M. (2016). Understanding open source communities as complex adaptive systems: A case of the R Project community. In AMCIS 2016 Proceedings. San Diego, CA. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2016/Open/Presentations/7/
- 2015 Link, G. J.P., Siemon, D., de Vreede, G.-J., & Robra-Bissantz, S. (2015). Evaluating Anchored Discussion to Foster Creativity in Online Collaboration. In N. Baloian, Y. Zorian, P. Taslakian, & S. Shoukouryan (Eds.), Collaboration and Technology (pp. 28–44). Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-22747-4_3

OTHER PUBLICATIONS (1)

2018 Ahuja, V., Marti, D., Link, G. J.P., Germonprez, M., & Goggins, S. P. (2018, May 23). How to measure the impact of your open source project. Retrieved May 23, 2018, from https://opensource.com/article/18/5/metrics-project-success

PRESENTATIONS (16)

- 2018 Raniere Silva, & Link, G. J.P. (2018, October). Open Community Metrics and Privacy. Presented at the Mozilla Festival, London, UK.
- 2018 Link, G. J.P., Izquierdo-Cortazar, D., Irwin, E., & Foster, D. (2018, October). Tutorial: How to Prepare a Diversity and Inclusion Report for your Community. Presented at the Open Source Summit Europe 2018, Edinburgh, UK. Retrieved from https://sched.co/FxYK
- 2018 Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2018, August). Chaos or CHAOSS: What we hear from the CHAOSS Community. Presented at the CHAOSScon North America 2018, Vancouver, BC, Canada. https://chaoss.github.io/website/CHAOSScon/2018NA/slides/Chaos-or-CHAOSS.pdf
- 2018 Link, G. J.P. (2018, March). Engaging Volunteers and Voluntolds in Open Source Projects. Presented at the 10th Annual Research and Creative Activity Fair, University of Nebraska at Omaha, NE, USA. https://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/srcaf/2018/schedule/148/
- 2017 Germonprez, M., & Link, G. J.P. (2017, September). BoF: Community Health Analytics for Open Source. Birds-of-a-Feather presented at the Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, California. Retrieved from http://sched.co/BCsP
- 2017 Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). Understanding organization and open source community relations through the Attraction-Selection-Attrition Model. Presented at OpenSym 2017, Galway, Ireland.
- 2017 Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). The value of engaging with open source communities. Presented at the OpenSym 2017 Doctoral Consortium, Galway, Ireland.
- 2017 Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. Presented at the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems, Boston, MA.
- 2017 Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2017, May). Advancing open online community science practice: The open community data exchange. Presented at the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference. Springfield, IL.

2017 Link, G. J.P. (2017, May). Measuring adoption of open source software and practices in organizations: A pilot study. Presented at the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference. Springfield, IL. 2016 Link, G. J.P. (2016, December). Moving Open Source Communities: How Foundations Onboard Communities. Presented at the SIGOPEN Developmental Workshop at ICIS 2016, Dublin, Ireland. 2016 Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2016, December). Communication Technology Selection in a Young Open Source Community: A Case of the Hyperledger Project. Presented at the SIGOPEN Developmental Workshop at ICIS 2016, Dublin, Ireland. 2016 Link, G. J.P. (2016, August). The Open Community Data Exchange: Advancing Data Sharing and Discovery in Open Online Community Science. Presented at the OpenSym 2016, Berlin, Germany. 2016 Link, G. J.P. (2016, April). The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities. Presented at the 14th Annual BigXII+MISResearchSymposium, Baylor University, Waco, TX, USA. 2016 Link, G. J.P. (2016, March). The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities. Presented at the 8th Annual Research and Creative Activity Fair, University of Nebraska at Omaha, NE, USA. http://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/srcaf/2016/Schedule/56/ 2015 Link, G. J.P. (2015, November). The Movement and Commoditization of Open Source Communities. Presented at the INFORMS Annual Meeting 2015, Philadelphia, PA, USA. 2018 NSF: Early-concept Grants for Exploratory Research (EAGER) ■ Title: Securing Critical Software Through Futures Markets ■ PI: Matt Germonprez ■ Unfunded proposal Mozilla Research Grants 2018H1 2018 ■ Title: Experiment on Introducing Project Health Signals and Price Signals in Open Source ■ PI: Georg Link Unfunded proposal Mozilla Open Source Experiments Program 2018 ■ Title: Experiment for Health Signals in Bugmark ■ PI: Georg Link ■ Unfunded proposal Alfred P. Sloan Foundation 2017 ■ Title: Open Source Project Health and Sustainability PI: Matt Germonprez and Sean Goggins ■ Funded with \$449,351 (2018-2020) 2017 **GRACA** internal grant University of Nebraska at Omaha ■ Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA) ■ Title: The Changing Nature of Volunteerism in Open source Communities ■ PI: Georg Link Funded with \$5,000 (2017) **GRACA** internal grant University of Nebraska at Omaha 2016 Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA) ■ Title: The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities ■ PI: Georg Link Unfunded proposal 2014 **BMBF** (German Federal Ministry of Education and Research) ■ Title: DETHIS - Design Thinking for Industrial Services ■ PI: Christoph Lattemann

■ Project number 01FJ15100 funded with 1.6 million Euro (2016-2019)

ACADEMIC **APPOINTMENTS**

GRANT WRITING

EXPERIENCE

University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA

- Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant
 - · Funded by Alfred P. Sloan Foundation and Mozilla

2015 – present

WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany

Visiting Lecturer for Information Systems

2014 – present

Technical University Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany

	 Research Assistant Institute of Business Information Systems — Information Management Group 	2014 – 2015
	 Research and Teaching Assistant Institute of Operating Systems and Computer Networks — Algorithms Group Comparing Linear Programming Solvers: CPLEX, Gurobi, and COIN-OR 	2013 – 2014
	 Research Assistant Institute of Business Information Systems — Decision Support Group 	2011 – 2012
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	Managing the Database Environment ■ University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA	2017 – 2018
	Organizations, Applications, and Technology ■ University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA	2017
	Introduction to Microsoft Excel■ WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany	2014 – Present
	Teaching Assistant: Algorithms and Data Structures ■ Technische Universität Braunschweig, Germany	2013 – 2014
PROFESSIONAL UNIVERSITY	UNO Mozilla Club , University of Nebraska at Omaha ■ Founder and Vice-President	2018 – Present
ACTIVITIES	Graduate College Committee , University of Nebraska at Omaha ■ Student Representative	2016 – 2018
	UCRCA Committee (internal grants), University of Nebraska at Omaha■ Student Representative	2016 – 2017
	PhD Student Group, University of Nebraska at OmahaFounder and President	2015 – 2017
PROFESSIONAL ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES	Executive ■ Communications Director, AIS SIGOPEN	2015 – Present
ACTIVITIES	 Organizing (Conference and Workshop) CHAOSScon North America Organizing Committee CHAOSScon Europe Organizing Committee Workshop on Open Community Health OpenSym Program Committee AMCIS Minitrack Co-Chair Minitrack: Peer Production Project Health OpenSym Program Committee and Session Chair SIGOPEN Pre-ICIS Workshop on Open Phenomena 	2018 2018 2018 2018 2018 2017
	Reviewing for Journals 2018 Information and Organization Information Technology for Development Journal of the Association for Information Systems Journal of Organizational Computing and Electronic Commerce	2018
	 HMD Praxis der Wirtschaftsinformatik 2017 Information Technology for Development Information & Management International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Small Business International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction 	2017
	 HMD Praxis der Wirtschaftsinformatik 2017 Information Technology for Development Information & Management International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Small Business 	2017

	■ 2015: ECIS	2015
	Conference Volunteering ACM Group OpenSym Big XII+ MIS Research Symposium International Conference on Information Systems	2018 2017 2017 2016
	 International Conference on Web Intelligence and International Conference on Brain Informatics & Health Coalition of Urban and Metropolitan Universities 	2016 2015
PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS	Association for Information Systems (AIS) ■ AIS SIGOPEN ■ Midwest United States Association for Information Systems (MWAIS)	2016 – Present
	Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)	2016 – Present
INDUSTRY TRAINING & CERTIFICATES	 Bankkaufmann Certified by Chamber of Commerce, Braunschweig, Germany Bankhaus C. L. Seeliger, Wolfenbüttel, Germany 	2008 – 2011
	 Ausbilder-Eignungsprüfung Certified by Chamber of Commerce, Braunschweig, Germany WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany 	2011
INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE	Freelance Web Developer ■ Custom Websites and Web Applications • Drupal, Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript	2007 – 2018
	 Claas of America, Omaha, NE, USA Internship in Warranty Department Analyzed years of warranty data using SAP export and MS Excel business intelligence features. Updated and improved usability of online warranty claim submission manual. Automated monthly reports in MS Excel with VBA-Programming. 	2013
	 VDLUFA Qualitätssicherung NIRS GmbH, Kassel, Germany Java Developer Programmed a Java-Servlet server/client application for decentralized data management and analysis 	2011 ysis.
OPEN SOURCE ENGAGEMENT	Participated in Open Source Projects CHAOSS Project Bugmark Core Infrastructure Initiative Best Practices Badge Toolkit for YNAB Drupal OpenOffice.org	2017 – Present 2017 – Present 2017 – Present 2017 – Present 2009 – 2010 2006 – 2009
LANGUAGES	Attended Open Source Conferences Open Source Leadership Summit Open Source Summit North America Open Source Summit Europe Mozilla Festival (MozFest) FOSDEM CHAOSScon Europe CHAOSScon North America Sustain Summit English: Native German: Native	2017 2017, 2018 2017, 2018 2017, 2018 2018 2018 2018 2018 2018

REFERENCES

■ Matt Germonprez

Mutual of Omaha Associate Professor Information Systems and Quantitative Analysis University of Nebraska at Omaha mgermonprez@unomaha.edu

■ Sean Goggins

Associate Professor School of Information Science and Learning Technologies University of Missouri s@goggins.com

Brian Dorn

Associate Professor Computer Science University of Nebraska at Omaha bdorn@unomaha.edu

■ Robin A. Gandhi

Associate Professor Cybersecurity University of Nebraska at Omaha rgandhi@unomaha.edu



[CV last updated on 2018-12-12]